Abhi Reddy

★ abhireddy.io ■ abhi.reddy1@gmail.com in abhiramreddy • abhiram25

PROFILE

I'm a software engineer with multiple years of experience in both Ruby and JavaScript, and I have experience in API integrations and OAuth2 Authorization with multiple years of experience in the tech industry working in scrum/agile teams.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer, Poindexter Inc.

09/2021 - 11/2021

https://abhi-reddy1.medium.com/api-integrations-3ad6c4d0e1d0 &

Worked on the following for Poindexter Inc's product Gridabl deployed on Linode, which is a spreadsheet-like application for crunching numbers

- Prototyped API integrations with tools such as Tray.io and Paragon to integrate with applications such as Xero, Quickbooks, and Stripe to expedite the process of integrating third-party APIs
- Implemented Doorkeeper for OAuth2 provider functionality and JWT token authentication
- Researched Handsontable library to work with ReactJS to implement a data grid with a spreadsheet-like user experience
- Wrote well-tested and maintainable code with knowledge of MVC architecture, PostgreSQL, and Ruby on Rails

Associate Software Quality Assurance Engineer, Brightree LLC.

02/2020 - 04/2021

- Worked within an agile scrum team, acting as the quality advocate for the Brightree Patient Engagement team's functional component area
- Design and execute test plans, scenarios, and scripts
- Found issues, tracked their resolution, and then verified the outcome
- Wrote automated tests for Patient Engagement using Selenium

Full Stack Software Developer, Self-Employed

2016 - 2021

- Mello: Trello clone to create Kanban boards for collaboration (React/Redux, Node/Express, MongoDB, Mongoose)
- To-Do App single page to-do tracking application (Node.js, Express.js, JavaScript, JQuery, Handlebars, HTML, and CSS)
- ARDevConnector Social network app for developers (MongoDB, Express.js, React, Node.js, Twilio, SendGrid, HTML, and CSS)

QA Analyst, PowerPlan Inc.

02/2017 - 01/2020

- Coordinated, participated, and provided feedbacks during reviews of business requirements, functional, technical, and design documents
- Performed Unit, Functional, Integration, System Integration, and User acceptance testing
- Identified defects and supported developers in resolving problems by completing additional tests

SKILLS

Backend Node.js, Express, MongoDB, PostreSQL, Ruby on Rails, SQL, RESTful APIs Front End
Javascript, HTML, CSS,
React/Redux, Handlebars.js,
jQuery

ToolsGit, Github, GitLab, Notion,
Jira, Postman, Selenium, Docker

Cloud Heroku AWS DigitalOcrean

EDUCATION

Launch School 2016 – 2021

Multi-year software engineering program with emphasis on mastery of core concepts through written assessments, live coding interviews, and take-home projects

Marketing, Georgia State University

2014 Atlanta, GA